Aditya Narayan Singh

Newtown• Kolkata, 700136• West Bengal 9794742245 • 6380563849 adityanarayansingh065@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

To work and contribute to the company's growth where I have the freedom to keep learning. I have a strong hold on Azure cognitive services development and Azure Bot development using MS Bot Framework SDK, Composer, PVA. Also I have expertise in Azure cognitive services, Azure Al Search and Azure OpenAI(Chatgpt, completion models, embedding models).

EDUCATION

JIS College of Engineering, Kalyani, WB — BCA AUGUST 2014 - AUGUST 2017 Score: 78.5% C Programming, C++, Numerical Methods, Software Process Management, Database Management System, E-commerce.

ST. Xavier's School, Ballia, UP —Higher Secondary JUNE 2011 - MAY 2013 **Score**: 65.8% English, Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Physical Health Education.

Gyan Peethika Sr. Sec. School, Ballia, UP — Secondary JUNE 2010 - MAY 2011 **Score**: 81.7% English, Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Biology, Computer Science.

SKILLS

Chatbot and Voice bot development (IVR) with live agent hand-off

Microsoft Bot Framework SDK, Azure Al Search, Azure OpenAl, Azure Cognitive Services, Chatgpt, Embeddings, LLM

Microsoft Bot Composer, PVA and Power automate flows

C# (.net framework), Python and Node.js

PostgreSQL, SQL

EXPERIENCES

Accenture: 31st May 2021- today

Promoted (November 2022): Application development Team Lead

- I am managing team of more than 20 people focus on GenAl development activity and working as technical lead of a COE team as well as look into delivery projects based on the requirements and work directly with client and sales team to propose estimates and solution during sales phase of the projects.
- I have experienced building RAG patterns using multiple Vector DB where we stored embeddings that were generated from files in various format such as docx, pdf, ppt, images etc.
- I am currently using Azure OpenAI model such as GPT-4-Turbo with Vision, GPT-3.5 and other completion model for generating abstractive summarizations.
- On embedding side, I am mostly using ada-002 but from start of the OpenAI journey
 I was leading the team so got to do hands-on almost all embedding models
- Solutioning assets and products for business problems of different domain like retail, healthcare, and Banking.
- Part of several private preview program with Microsoft Azure where I work closely with Microsoft's cognitive services development team and help them improve the product.

Designation: Application development senior consultant

- Task is mostly building escalators for Chatbot and Voice bot development using Microsoft's cognitive services, Azure Al Search, CLU, Custom QnA, Azure function apps and other Azure PaaS services.
- Successfully completed POC for a Supermarket chain in Europe and an alcohol beverage company.
- Worked on developing adapters for converting Chatbot to voice bot using third party IVR service provider such as Twilio.
- Worked on voice authentication of voice bot using Nuance's biometric authentication.

AstraZeneca India Pvt Ltd. 25Mar 2019- 28May 2021

Designation: Associate Engineer (Al developer)

I use LUIS, Cognitive services and other applied ML algorithms to develop chatbots.

- **Contract FAQ Chatbot:** Chatbot was deployed on a salesforce site it was a simple FAQ chatbot that helps visitors in guiding through the form fill up process.
- Conflict of Interest Chatbot: Chatbot was developed to answer issues that could be conflicting in organisation. Chatbot has a separate flow for different hierarchical levels of employees. With capability of auto suggestion without using any paid services.
- **Automation of Chatbot training:** Wrote an azure function and have shared Api details to customers, where without any technical knowledge one can train the chatbot for new questions.
- **Auto commenting Chatbot:** Did a POC where chatbot can reply to queries posted on Facebook.
- **Legal & Procurement Chatbot:** Developed chatbot that got deployed to help users in translating polish legal terms to English, defines jargons used in industry.
- AskFinance Chatbot: Simple FAQ as well as guided chatbot for financial queries with capability of auto suggestion while typing.
- Analytic conversation bot: Chatbot was integrated with Snaplogic to read data and performed and summarised data for representation in chat windows.
- Automation of search indexing and table update in Azure: Users with a specific
 phrase can trigger these both automation from chatbot itself where it updates, deletes
 or updates rows from azure table that has been maintained for auto suggestion and
 afterwards run indexer.

Cognizant Technology Solutions, Chennai 07Sep 2017-11Mar 2019

Designation: Programmer

Task was to clean up the data and perform data engineering on datasets accumulating from different sources.

CDI — Python script, automation for integrity check of dataset: Script pickups
the data arrived in zip folder from different sources and check for standard naming

convention and verifies it against data available in config file, after that it unzip it and trigger integrity check macros for each dataset that has been extracted from zip file and after successful verification move the files to end user location and send a mail to listed user in config file with log message that's been logged throughout the script.

- SAS dataset Generation Using Python for the use of BU: Developed a python script which was collecting data from various database sources like oracle, text files, Mysql and was merging data based on metadata stored in oracle database then converting all sources in one SAS format which could be used by hierarchical people for decision making.
- Point in time was a python script which was to automate the task of uploading
 archive data to AWS glacier from it could be retrieved if required. Developed script
 has CLI interface through which user can specify the path of archive data if need to be
 uploaded else provide the option which then followed by credential verification to
 download archive data from AWS glacier.

RESEARCH WORKS

- Work is a pioneering approach to develop an application for message transference.
 The eminence of the work lies in ensuring that the messages sent are in an encrypted format and when intended recipient of message gets would be able to decrypt using designed android application. Research work is published under IEEE in year 2018 isbn no.: 978-1-5386-5657-0/18
- Written technical blogs for C programs: dotcprograms.blogspot.com and Python scripting for data analytics: py3programs.blogspot.com have been visited by 4 lakhs visitors and counting.

Awards

- Accenture Data and Al Hackathon winner 2023.
- Runner up in CODEFLUENZA Inter-College Techfest 2017. It was a coding competition consisting of three sets of problems where participants were free to choose the programming language, Received certificate of runner up.
- Winner of Intra-Departmental Android application development seminar followed up with competition. Received token of appreciation with certificate.

• Second Runner up in CODEFLUENZA (coding competition) Inter-College Techfest 2016.

Languages Known: English, Hindi, Bengali, Tamil (Read & Write).

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/adityasingh06/